在干嘛呢
Whatcha doin' there?
研究抓哔哔鸟的新方法吗
Working on a new plan to catch the roadrunner?
你这个幽默暗指我是大笨狼怀尔吗
The humorous implication being that I am Wile E. Coyote?
没错
Yes.
而板上画的捕鸟设备
And this is a schematic for a bird-trapping device
最终只会适得其反  让我受伤吗
that will ultimately backfire and cause me physical injury?
没错
Yes.
我正在做的
What I'm doing here
是想计算出我的死亡时间
is trying to determine when I'm going to die.
很多人都在做这方面的研究
A lot of people are working on that research.
那这些是什么
So what is all this?
我家人的寿命长短
My family history factoring in longevity
疾病倾向等信息
propensity for disease, et cetera.
有意思
Interesting.
卡尔叔叔的死因是KBB
Cause of death for Uncle Carl was KBB.
KBB是什么
What's "KBB"?
被獾所杀
"Killed by badger."
怎么回事
How's that?
那是感恩节
It was Thanksgiving.
卡尔叔叔说"我觉得有只獾住在咱家烟囱里"
Uncle Carl said, "I think there's a badger living in our chimney. "
"把手电筒给我"
"Hand me that flashlight."
那是他对我们说的最后几句话
Those were the last words he ever spoke to us.
我觉得
I don't think you need
你没必要担心被獾所杀会遗传
to worry about death by badgers being hereditary.
不对
Not true.
战斗或逃跑的本能受基因控制
The fight or flight instinct is coded genetically.
他没选择逃跑  反而赤手空拳
Instead of fleeing, he chose to fight barehanded
跟鼬类动物中强壮的一员战斗
against a brawny member of the weasel family.
谁能肯定我没遗传这种有缺陷的基因
Who's to say that I don't share that flawed DNA?
你反正可以找只獾来验证的
You can always get a badger and find out.
说实在的
But seriously
即使我忽略卡尔叔叔这个因素
even if I disregard the Uncle Carl factor
我最多也只剩60年寿命
at best I have 60 years left.
还有那么长啊
That long, huh?
60年我只能活到这里
60 only takes me to here.
我要活到这里
I need to get to here.
那里有什么
What's there?
据预计奇点最早出现的时间
The earliest estimate of the singularity
人们能将自己的意识
when man will be able to transfer his consciousness
转移进机器而获得永生
into machines and achieve immortality.
这么说  你不高兴自己会错失
So, you're upset about missing out
变成某种怪异的有自我意识的机器人的机会
on becoming some sort of freakish self-aware robot?
就差这么一点啊
By this much.
真可惜  你要吃鸡蛋吗
Tough break.  You want eggs?
你不明白  莱纳德
You don't get it, Leonard.
我会错过很多东西
I'm going to miss so much.
统一场论  冷聚变  还有章狗
the unified field theory, cold fusion, the dogapus.
章狗是什么
What's a dogapus?
狗和章鱼的杂交动物
The hybrid dog and octopus.
人类在水下的忠实朋友
Man's underwater best friend.
有人研究这个吗
Is somebody working on that?
我打算过研究的
I was going to.
我想把它作为我三百岁的生日礼物
I planned on giving it to myself on my 300th birthday.
等等  你讨厌狗
Wait a minute. You hate dogs.
章狗玩接球时能接八个球
A dogapus can play fetch with eight balls.
没有人能讨厌这个
No one can hate that.
生活大爆炸
第四季第二集
我们欠你多少钱
What do we owe you?
一共是28.17美元
It came to $28.17.
每人就六美元吧
Let's say six bucks apiece.
给你
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
干嘛
What?
算了  我请了
Never mind. I got it.
你要我给钱啊
Oh, you wanted me to pay.
-不用了  -不不不  你是对的
- It's no big deal. - No, no, no, no. You're right.
我们已经分手了  我应该自己付钱
We're not going out anymore; I should pay for myself.
笑什么
What?
他说"如果他有女人身子"
He said, "If he had woman parts
"他后半辈子就不愁吃了"
"he'd eat for free the rest of his life"
是啊  可你也没办法跟自己说话了
Yeah, but you wouldn't be able to talk to yourself.
我现金有点紧张啊
I'm a little low on cash.
-你有多少  -没有
- How much you got?  - Nothing.
你不带钱怎么出门啊
How can you walk around with no money?
我漂亮  别人请客
I'm cute. I get by.
没事  欠着吧
It's okay, you can owe me.
-谢谢  -谢尔顿  六美元
- Thank you.  - Sheldon, six bucks.
不了  谢谢  我今晚不吃披萨
No, thank you. I'm not eating pizza tonight.
可今天是星期四
But it's Thursday.
星期四是披萨之夜
Thursday's pizza night.
对我来说不是
Not for me.
现在改成十字花科蔬菜之夜了
Thursday is now Cruciferous Vegetable Night.
今晚的特选  小包菜
Tonight's selection: Brussels sprouts.
真的吗
Really?
你要改谢尔顿日程表
You're changing the Sheldonian calendar?
-这只是个小小的代价  -为啥
- It's a small price to pay. - For what?
-不  别问啊  -对不起
- No, no, don't ask. - Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
为了把我的寿命延长到能把意识
In order to live long enough to fuse my consciousness
转移到人造大脑上  我要改变饮食
with cybernetics, I need to change my diet.
等等  人造大脑是机器人之类的吧
Wait. Cybernetics is robot stuff, right?
没错
Correct.
这么说你想把自己变成某种机器人
So you want to turn yourself into some sort of robot?
本质上是这样
Essentially, yes.
我想问个问题
Okay, here's my question.
你不是已经变成机器人了吗
Didn't you already do that?
虽然我受宠若惊  可惜还没有
Flattering, but sadly, no.
我还打算开始一种运动养生法
I'm also planning to begin an exercise regimen
加强我的心血管系统
designed to strengthen my cardiovascular system.
也就是慢跑
AKA jogging.
等等  亲爱的  你以前跑过步吗
Wait. Honey, have you ever run before?
当然跑过
Certainly.
我被恶霸  狗和暴走的鸡追过
I've run from bullies, dogs, angry chickens...
还有个锲而不舍执意要给我做
and one particularly persistent P.E. teacher
脊柱侧弯测试的体育老师
determined to bend me over and give me a scoliosis test.
你说得对  佩妮经常跑步
You're right. Penny jogs.
你们可以一起跑的
Maybe you guys can run together.
这主意太棒了
That's an excellent idea.
如果我们边跑边聊
Yeah, if we chat
就会感觉时间流逝得更快了
it will create the illusion of time going faster.
绝对不可能
No, it won't.
他怎么知道我跑步的
Um, how does he know I jog?
因为他在车里用高倍望远镜尾行你
Oh, he watches you from his car with high-powered binoculars.
我的天呐  这太猥琐了
Oh, my God, that is so creepy!
我就说嘛
I know!
他说他要坚持发扬下去
And he says he's not gonna stop.
那找心理医生解决怎么和女人说话的问题啊
Then see a shrink and figure out how to talk to women.
什么玩意儿
What the hell?
怎么了
What's the matter?
疼痛以我的肚脐为起点
I have pain radiating from my navel
延伸到我的右下腹
to my lower right abdomen.
我感到恶心和发热
I'm nauseated and feverish.
我觉得我得霍乱了
I believe I may have cholera.
帕萨迪纳才没霍乱呢
There's no cholera in Pasadena.
就跟去年夏天帕萨迪纳也没有疟疾一样
Just like last summer, when there was no malaria in Pasadena.
好吧  如果那不是霍乱
Well, if it's not cholera
根据搜索结果
then based on a quick Internet search
由相似度递减排列的其他解释分别是
the other explanations in decreasing order of likelihood
先天性巨结肠  肉毒杆菌中毒  一条30英尺长的绦虫
are Hirschsprung's Disease, botulism, a 30-foot tapeworm
或者是不小心摄入菊花
or accidental ingestion of chrysanthemum blossoms.
你什么时候会不小心摄入菊花的
When would you have accidentally eaten chrysanthemum blossoms?
这是包括了梦游
It's part of an unlikely scenario
和24小时营业的花店
that involves sleepwalking and a 24-hour flower mart
以及不靠谱的经营者的不可能场景
with a less-than- vigilant proprietor.
噢  老天  我的肚子
Oh, Lord, my belly!
你切除过阑尾吗
Ever had your appendix out?
没有
I haven't.
我想来着  但谁有那时间啊
I've been meaning to, but who has the time?
我送你去医院吧
Let's get you to the hospital.
于是乎就此了结
So this is how it ends...
真是无比残酷的讽刺
with cruel irony.
正当我保证要保护爱惜自己的身体之时
Just as I make the commitment to preserving my body
我被自己的阑尾所背叛  就一退化的器官
I am betrayed by my appendix, a vestigial organ.
你知道阑尾原本的作用是什么吗  莱纳德
Do you know the original purpose of the appendix, Leonard?
不知道
No.
我知道  而知道太多的却灭亡而你却能继续活下去
I do. And yet I'm doomed while you live on.
结局很出乎意料  是不是
Funny how things work out, isn't it?
噢  天呐  我感觉要爆炸了
Oh, Lord, I think it's about to burst!
还有种可能
On the other hand
也许都是小包菜的错
it might have been the Brussels sprouts.
晚安您呐
Good night.
晚安
阑尾炎
Appendicitis.
自己紧张个甚啊
What a nervous Nelly.
佩妮  佩妮  佩妮
Penny! Penny! Penny!
来啦  来啦
Coming, coming.
嘿  跑鞋不错嘛
Hey, nice knees.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我娘的
They're my mother's.
闪电侠T恤是什么意思
Oh. And the Flash shirt is what?
你要跑的飞快吗
Because, what, you're gonna run really fast?
不是  穿闪电侠衫是因为今天是星期五
No, the Flash shirt is because it's Friday
但要是真能有效就更好了
but it's nice when things work out.
-你的心率监测器在哪儿  -没有
- Where's your heart rate monitor?  - I don't have one.
-计步器呢  -没有
- What about your pedometer?  - Don't have one.
那你鞋子里有传感器连接到iPod吗
Do you have telematics in your shoes connected to an iPod?
-没  -那你干嘛呢
- Uh, no.  - What do you do
就出去像兔子一样随便蹦蹦跳跳一下吗
You just go out there and gambol about like a bunny?
不  也就跑到饿了  然后买个熊爪包吃
No. I just run till I'm hungry, then I stop for a bear claw.
为什么要这么做
Why are you doing that?
在跑步前最好拉伸下肌肉
It's good to stretch your muscles before you run.
好吧
All right.
先来摸个脚趾
Let's start with a toe touch.
你来做一个
Okay, you do it.
我正做着呢
I am doing it.
哇哦  不错
Oh. Wow. Good job.
你能做这个么
Can you do this?
我们永远也不会知道的
We'll never know.
好吧  那边跑边热身吧
Okay, let's just warm up on the run.
-好的  -那出发吧
- Okay.  - Okay, let's go.
我最近一直在读生物力学的书
I've been reading up on biomechanics.
我认为你会惊讶于我的...
I think you'll be surprised at my...
我的天呐  你还好吗
Oh, my God, are you okay?
应该吧
I think so.
-我来拉你一把吧  -谢谢
- Oh, let me help you up.  - Thank you.
噢  谢尔顿
Oh, Sheldon!
如果这能让你觉得好些的话
If it makes you feel any better
星期四不再是十字花科蔬菜之夜了
Thursday is no longer Cruciferous Vegetable Night.
这是我的咖喱鸡
Here's my chicken curry.
霍华德的鲜虾菜饭
Howard, your shrimp biryani.
-谢谢您  -菠菜奶豆腐  是佩妮的
- Thank you, sir.  - Palak paneer, that's Penny.
-谢谢  -而拉杰·库萨帕里的
- Thanks.  - And for Rajesh Koothrappali
家乡发明出这些美味佳肴的人
from whose homeland these tasty dishes originate
一个大份的麦乐鸡
one large order of chicken McNuggets.
-我的这份多少钱  -12刀
- Hey, what's my share?  - Uh... 12 bucks.
-我能周五付工资以后再还你吗  -没问题
- Okay, can I get you after Friday when I get paid?  - Sure.
我欠你多少了
What am I up to now?
呃  算上印度菜  比萨
Well, okay, with the Indian food, the pizza
泰国菜  一箱油
the Thai food, the tank of gas
冷冻酸奶
the frozen yogurt
外带你的房租  嗯...
and your rent, uh...
一千四百多一点吧
a little over $1,400.
又怎么了
What now?
他只是表示膜拜
He's just expressing his admiration that
你不用献身也能蹭吃蹭喝
you don't even have to put out to get free stuff.
我这不是蹭  我会还钱的
It's not free-- I'm gonna pay him back.
给我停
Shut up!
谢尔顿  你不来吗
Sheldon, are you gonna join us?
就来
Coming!
你们好  伙计们
Greetings, friends.
你好  你个天知道是什么的鬼东西
Greetings, whatever the hell you are.
我是一个移动虚拟化身设备
I am a mobile virtual presence device.
鉴于近来发生的事
Recent events
我意识到我的肉身太过脆弱
have demonstrated to me that my body is too fragile
承受不了大千世界的种种
to endure the vicissitudes of the world.
因此  在我能够
Until such time as I am able
转移意识之前
to transfer my consciousness
我的肉身将保存在一个安全地点
I shall remain in a secure location
并借此方式同外界联系
and interact with the world in this manner.
没搞错吧  你就想问这个--
Really? That's your question--
他啥时搞来的那个斜坡
when did he put a ramp in?
你占了我的专属座位
You're in my spot.
可能一开始感觉会有点怪
This may seem a little odd at first
但时间久了  你们就会渐渐习惯
but over time, you'll grow accustomed
和这样的我打交道
to dealing with me in this configuration.
是咩  说实话  我觉得没什么不同
Yeah, to be honest, I don't see much difference.
谢谢
Thank you.
这也是我的目的
That's what I was going for.
那个  莱纳德  明天我们去上班时
Now, Leonard, tomorrow, when we go to work
你得腾出点时间来
you'll need to allow some extra time
把我搬下楼梯
to get me down the stairs.
为了让你省力  我会分解成四个部分
For your convenience, I disassemble into four pieces.
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
我要去找你谈谈
I'm coming to talk to you.
你不知道我在哪儿
You don't know where I am.
我的肉身现被安置在
My physical body is safely ensconced
一个安全保密的场所
in a secure, undisclosed location.
你不就在你卧室里么
You're in your bedroom.
不  我不在
No, I'm not.
我都能听到你说话的声音从卧室传出来
I can hear your voice coming from your bedroom.
不  你听不到
No, you can't.
你给我等着
Wait.
回来
Come back.
站住
Halt.
未经授权人员禁止入内
Authorized personnel only!
好吧  你们两个变态
So, either one of you weirdos
有谁想买我的内衣么  只要一千四百块哦
want to buy my underwear? Only 1,400 bucks.
谢尔顿  这太荒唐了
Sheldon, this is ridiculous.
我在你后面
I'm behind you.
和我说话时请看着我
Please look at me when you're talking to me.
我正看着你呢
I am looking at you.
不  你没有
No, you're not.
无视床上的那个人
Pay no attention to that man in the bed.
你不能以这种方式存在于这世上
You cannot exist as a virtual presence.
这儿不行  工作时就更不行了
Not here and certainly not at work.
我的娘咧
Oh, good God.
你知不知道  我这年纪的人
At my age, do you know
统计数字上最可能怎么死吗
how I'm statistically most likely to die?
被你室友做掉吗
At the hands of your roommate?
死于一场意外
An accident.
我就准备弄成像是一场意外
That's how I'm going to make it look.
在我将自己的智慧
Until I can transfer my intellect
转移到一个更持久的容器内之前
to a more durable container
我的肉身将被安全安置在我的床上
my body will remain safely ensconced in my bed.
随你  但别指望我会帮你
Fine, but don't expect my help.
你必须帮我  室友协议里写了
You have to help-- it's in the roommate agreement.
不  才没有
No, it's not.
74条C款
Section 74.C.
两人间若有人成了机器人
The various obligations and duties of the parties
另一人所应尽的各项义务和责任
in the event one of them becomes a robot.
让我一头撞死好了
I'll be damned.
这种感觉太赞了
This is delightful.
哼哼
Uh-huh.
不用担心死于车祸
It's much easier to enjoy
这样在上班路中欣赏美景
the picturesque route we travel to work
就更加怡然自得了
when you remove the specter of fiery vehicular death.
提醒我下
Refresh my memory.
我干嘛不直接把你塞进后备箱呢
Why didn't I just put you in the trunk?
因为我先抢了前排座位  记得不
Because I called shotgun. Remember?
好吧
Right.
你看着压力很大
You seem tense.
这样会不会感到放松
Perhaps this will relax you.
我不想听音乐  谢尔顿
I don't want to listen to music, Sheldon.
好吧
Very well.
真不明白你为什么不喜欢这样
I don't understand why you're not enjoying this.
你和增强功能的我  一起在车里
Together, in this car, with my enhanced capabilities
这就好比霹雳游侠嘛
we're like Knight Rider.
那里面的车可不是括约肌吱吱响的废柴
Except in Knight Rider, the car isn't a yammering sphincter.
你居然嘲笑括约肌
You mock the sphincter
括约肌可是人体的一组肌肉
but the sphincter is a class of muscle
没有的话人类没法存活的哦
without which human beings couldn't survive.
人体内共有超过50种
There are over 50 different sphincters
不同的括约肌
in the human body.
你能叫出多少
How many can you name?
我错了  这就是一霹雳游侠  没说的
I was wrong-- this is exactly like Knight Rider.
你大概会对另一个游戏感兴趣
Perhaps you'd be interested in a different game.
没兴趣
No.
这张照片  是在1911年
This is a photograph of the 1911
召开的辐射和量子理论索尔瓦会议
Solvay Conference on the theory of radiation and quanta.
我PS了几处不该存在的东西
Using Photoshop, I've introduced a few anachronisms.
看看你能不能找出所有24处
See if you can spot all 24.
我先给你第一个提示好了
I'll give you the first one.
居里夫人不该带着电子表
Madame Curie should not be wearing a digital watch.
你继续吧
And go.
够了  拜拜
That's it. Bye-bye.
吓死你
Bazinga.
我有更高权限的开关
I have an override switch.
我差点被你害死了
I almost died!
而我仍安然无恙地坐在床上
And I'm safe and sound in bed.
现在再看谁是疯子
Who's crazy now?
我还是会说你
I'm still going to go with you.
你好  霍斯金斯教授
Hello, Professor Hoskins.
很高兴见到你  敏迪
Nice to see you, Mindy.
早上好[日语]  中村博士
And konnichiwa, Dr. Nakamura.
很遗憾那帮瑞典佬推翻了你的理论
Sorry the Swedes disproved your theory.
莱纳德  我的门
Leonard, my door.
你的门怎么了
What about it?
乖  给哥开个门
Be a lamb and open it for me.
为嘛  有啥问题吗
Why? What's the problem?
你以为你难住我了  对吗
You think you have me stymied, don't you?
没有啊  我觉得难住你的是门把手
No, I think a doorknob has you stymied.
哦  看啊  莱纳德和R2-D-Bag[代指《星战》里的R2-D2机器人]
Oh, look, it's Leonard and R2-D-Bag.
这笑话是我想出来的  我昨晚给你讲的
That's my joke. I told it last night.
你不能随便剽窃好吧
You can't just use it.
拉杰  乖  替哥开下门
Raj, be a lamb and open the door for me.
好的
Oh, sure.
他真乖
He's a lamb.
你不乖
You're not.
我好乖哦
I'm a lamb.
这一切多美好啊
Isn't this nice?
在享受同伴感情的同时
The pleasures of fellowship and camaraderie
又不必忍受你们污浊呼吸对我皮肤的伤害
without having to tolerate your germy breath on my skin.
要我说咱们把他送到塔图因星球上
I say we just take him to Tatooine
把他卖给爪哇人吧[《星战》情节]
and sell him to some Jawas.
第二次了  老兄
That's two, dude.
写你自己的笑话去
Write your own jokes.
哎呦欸
Oh, great.
嗨  我叫佩妮  今晚为你们服务
Hi, I'm Penny, I'll be your waitress.
你干嘛还要作自我介绍啊
Why are you introducing yourself?
不管怎么样  我宁愿
I'd rather people not know
大家都不知道我跟你们之前有任何联系
I have any prior connection to you whatsoever.
你能介绍一下今晚有什么特色菜吗
Can you tell me the specials this evening?
谢尔顿  我不为你服务
Sheldon, I'm not waiting on you.
当然了
Obviously.
你还没给我倒水呢
I don't even have water yet.
因为你不在这里
Because you're not here.
你这是对远程遥控人员的歧视
That's discrimination against the otherwise located.
我要去找你的领导[也有比你高的意思]
I'm going to have to go over your head.
经理  经理在吗
Manager... manager.
天啊  快看那是谁
Oh, Lord, look who it is.
那是斯蒂夫·沃兹尼亚克吗[苹果公司创始人之一]
Is that Steve Wozniak?
我猜没错
I think it is.
神奇而伟大的沃兹啊
The Great and Powerful Woz.
佩妮  斯蒂夫·沃兹尼亚克
Penny, Steve Wozniak was
可是苹果电脑公司的创始人之一呢
one of the cofounders of Apple Computer.
-他和斯蒂夫·乔布斯一起创办了...  -没错
- He and Steve Jobs started it...  - Yeah
我知道他是谁  我看过《与星共舞》
I know who he is. I watch Dancing with the Stars.
我得去和他聊聊
I must speak to him.
你当然得去了
Of course you must.
这条街上还有家橄榄园[意大利连锁餐馆]
You know, there's an Olive Garden down the street.
你们有空应该去尝尝
You guys should try it sometime.
打扰了  沃兹尼亚克先生
Excuse me, Mr. Wozniak?
嘿
Oh, hey.
很不错的虚拟化身仪器
Nice virtual presence device.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
我想说我是你的忠实粉丝
I just want to say I'm a big fan.
你在我最爱的科技远见卓识者排行榜上排第15
You're my 15th favorite technological visionary.
才第15啊
Only 15th?
那也比斯蒂夫·乔布斯高6名呢
It's still six spots above Steve Jobs.
我既不喜欢高翻衣领  也不喜爱炫舞技的人
I care neither for turtlenecks nor showmanship.
嗯  我从来不穿高翻领的衣服
Yeah, I never got that turtleneck thing.
我最得意的收藏就是一台1977年产的苹果Ⅱ
One of my proudest possessions is a vintage 1977 Apple Two.
如果不考虑苹果DOS 3.3版文件系统的局限性
Despite the file system limitations of Apple DOS 3.3
它确实算个一流的小成就
it was a pretty nifty little achievement.
多谢  "一流"这个词让我受宠若惊
Thanks, we were shooting for "nifty."
如果你能把它带过来的话
You know, if you had it here
我可以在上面签个名
I'd autograph it for you.
别走开  等我15到30分钟
Don't move for 15 to 30 minutes
具体情况得看公交车的运营情况
depending on how the buses are running.
书呆子
Nerds.
我来了  沃兹  我来了
I'm coming, Woz, I'm coming.
佩妮  佩妮  佩妮
Penny... Penny... Penny.
怎么了  谢童木
What up, Shel-Bot?
我下不了床
I can't get out of bed.
脚扭了
I hurt my ankle.
你想让我干嘛啊
What do you want me to do?
给我唱"乖乖猫"吧
Sing me "Soft Kitty."
你真的想让我对着个电脑显示器唱
Really, you want me to sing "Soft Kitty"
"乖乖猫"吗
to a computer monitor?
你想过来当面对我唱吗
Would you rather come over and sing it to me in person?
乖乖猫  暖暖猫
Soft kitty, warm kitty
小小毛绒球
Little ball of fur...
离麦克风近点儿
Closer to the microphone.
快乐猫  瞌睡...
Happy kitty, sleepy...
打住
No.
从头开始
You have to start over.
乖乖猫  暖暖猫
Soft kitty, warm kitty
小小毛绒球
Little ball of fur
快乐猫  瞌睡猫
Happy kitty, sleepy kitty
呜  呜  呜[猫叫声]
Purr, purr, purr.